sasktel.com 2012-12-06

# Privacy - Legal and Regulatory - About Us -

Protecting your privacy and safeguarding your personal information is one of our highest priorities **

Table of Contents

**

  * Our Privacy Commitment to You 
  * Why We Collect Personal Information 
  * Sharing Your Personal Information 
  * SaskTel Personal Information Handling Principles 
  * What Are Your Choices? 
  * Your On-line Privacy on our web site 
  * IP Address 
  * Anonymous Information 
  * Cookies 
  * How We Safeguard Your Information 
  * Children 
  * Links to Other Web Sites 
  * Questions or Concerns 

##### Our Privacy Commitment to You 

SaskTel places a high priority on the loyalty of our customers, and that loyalty is built on a foundation of good products, competitive prices, and, above all, excellent customer service.   
Respecting your right to privacy is an important part of our service excellence commitment.  It is our goal to treat your personal information with the utmost respect. To us, this includes keeping you up-to-date on your rights as our customers and providing you with information on how we use your personal information. Our Privacy Statement outlines our commitment to protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information.   
SaskTel may update this statement from time to time as reflected in the date at the end of this document, so please review it periodically. You are also encouraged to review the Legal Notices and User Agreement provided on this web site. They too, are provided for your information and protection.   

##### Why We Collect Personal Information 

Personal information is defined as information about an identifiable individual. This includes information about your product and service subscriptions and usage. Publicly available information, such as a public telephone book listing of your name, address and telephone number, is not considered personal information.    
SaskTel collects information about you during the application process to confirm your identity and credit history, when communicating or transacting business with you, and when providing service to you. We may also collect information about you from third parties that have the right to disclose such information to us.  
Telephone calls to or from our service representatives may be monitored or recorded for quality assurance purposes.  We understand that some of this information is private, which is why we collect personal information only for the following purposes:   

  * To establish and maintain a responsible commercial relationship with you and to provide you with ongoing service. For example, we will collect information about you during the application process to conduct a credit history and / or when communicating or transacting business with you to confirm your identity; if you prefer to use pre-authorized payment for our services, we will collect bank account information in order to process payment. 
  * To understand your needs and develop and recommend suitable products and services. For example, we maintain a record of products and services you receive from us, and we may ask you for additional information so that we can serve you better. For instance, if you wish to view your bill using our electronic payment service, we will ask for your e-mail address. 
  * To manage your account and understand your needs and preferences **** allowing us to **** offer you **** better products and special offers that we think may be of interest to you. 
  * To manage and develop our business and operations, including personnel and employment matters. For example, we analyze the usage of our networks to plan for future growth. We also collect information from individuals who apply for jobs with SaskTel.
  * To meet legal and regulatory requirements. For example, we may collect information in order to respond to a court order. 

##### Sharing Your Personal Information 

Personal information is not sold or rented to any parties outside of the SaskTel corporate family, without your consent or as permitted by SaskTel's Tariff.   
We do share this information with the companies we select as our business partners, and who supply services to us. However, we require them by contract, to honour our privacy principles in the handling of personal information they obtain from us. The information provided to our business partners is used only for that purpose and any disclosure outside of SaskTel is made on a confidential basis **.** Should we sell a part of our business or merge or amalgamate part or all of our business with another entity, we may need to disclose customer information as part of the transaction. This is a normal business practice in any such transaction. Any such disclosure would be subject to appropriate privacy and security safeguards. In certain circumstances in which it is necessary to do so, or where permitted by law, we may disclose your personal information without your consent to the following parties: 

  * the customer or an agent acting on the customer's behalf, such as Power of Attorney; 
  * companies we select as our business partners;
  * a company that publishes a directory or directory-related services, 
  * a collection agency or party used to determine creditworthiness or, for collecting unpaid balances;
  * a credit bureau reporting agency
  * courts, law enforcement agencies or otherwise legally empowered entities; 
  * we may disclose personal information to meet legal or regulatory requirements, such as under a court order or, to a government institution if required or authorized by law;
  * to public authorities or their agents in cases of emergency e.g., a 911 call;
  * ombudsman

##### SaskTel Personal Information Handling Principles 

SaskTel has always been, and will continue to be, committed to the privacy of your personal information. In addition to our existing procedures and our adherence to The Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FOIP) which governs our approach to handling personal information, we have adopted the following privacy principles from the Canadian Standards Association's Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information: 

Principle 1 -Accountability   
SaskTel is responsible for the personal information under our control and has designated a Chief Privacy Officer (CPO) as being accountable for SaskTel's compliance with the privacy principles. 

Principle 2 -Identifying Purposes for the collection of personal information   
SaskTel will identify the purpose for collecting personal information at or before the time the information is collected. 

Principle 3 - Obtaining Consent for the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information   
We require the knowledge and consent of the customer for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information except where it is impractical or inappropriate to do such as in emergency situations. 

Principle 4 - Limiting Collection of Personal Information   
SaskTel will limit the collection of personal information to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by the company. SaskTel will collect personal information by fair and lawful means. 

Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention of Personal Information   
SaskTel will not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law. SaskTel retains personal information only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes. 

Principle 6 - Accuracy of Personal Information   
Personal information will be as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. 

Principle 7 -Security Safeguards   
SaskTel will protect personal information by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. 

Principle 8 - Openness   
SaskTel will make readily available to customers and employees, specific information about its policies and procedures relating to the management of personal information.   

Principle 9 - Customer and Employee Access to Personal Information   
Upon request, customers and employees shall be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information and shall be given access to that information. An individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. 

Principle 10 - Challenging Compliance   
A customer may address a challenge concerning compliance with the above principles to the Chief Privacy Officer. SaskTel personnel are required to complete mandatory privacy training courses, and general staff education and training, to enhance awareness of responsibilities and commitments towards the proper handling of customer's personal information in accordance with SaskTel's polices and procedures.   

##### What Are Your Choices? 

We would like to have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for the purposes that we have outlined. However, you do have choices. 

  * You can have your name removed from our telephone, mail or e-mail marketing lists. By doing so, you may not be made aware of certain products, services, and promotions offered by SaskTel. However, you will continue to be contacted as necessary to service your account, and you will receive marketing information included with your regular account mailings. Please allow us 30 days to complete your request. Some of our promotions may already be in progress when you submit your request, therefore you may be contacted during this time. If at any time you wish to reverse your decision, you may contact us at 1-800-352-7238. (SaskTel cellular customers may call 1-800-667-2355 to change their preferences) 
  * Our directory publisher, DirectWest, makes lists of published names, addresses and phone numbers available to selected organizations for a fee. You may choose to be excluded from these DirectWest lists. Please note that non-published names, addresses and phone numbers are automatically excluded. 
  * You may refuse to provide personal information to us. You may also withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal, contractual or practical restrictions and reasonable notice. However, in either case, this may limit our ability to serve you. 

When you contact us, we will confirm that you are the registered customer. Please know that withdrawing your consent may prevent us from providing you with service and products in certain circumstances. 

##### Your On-line Privacy on our web site 

SaskTel collects some information about the ways you use our web site in order to make our site more interesting and useful to you. You are welcome to browse our web site anonymously at any time, without revealing any personal information. 

There are a few activities where the collection of personally identifiable information may be necessary. When personally identifiable information is collected, you will know because you will have chosen to provide your information.   

##### IP Address 

When you visit our site, your IP address is collected so that we know where to send the information you are requesting. This IP address does not personally identify you. 

**Anonymous Information**

This is information that cannot be associated with a specific individual. Our web servers collect some anonymous information automatically when you visit our site. This information may include the pages you visited, what content you downloaded, the type of web browser you were using, and the level of encryption your browser supports. 

This information is collected on an aggregated basis. No personal information is associated with these statistics. We use this information to determine what type of information is most useful to you so that we can improve our web sites to make it easier for you to access information. 

**Cookies**

Our site collects aggregated site-visitation statistics using cookies, small text files containing a unique identification number that identifies your browser to our computers. This small file of information allows our web site to remember important information that will make your use of our site more enjoyable. 

Cookies tell us which pages are visited, by how many people, the average time spent, and other useful statistics relating to the use of our site. This information does not identify you or link you personally to products or services purchased through sasktel.com. All gathered information is captured on an anonymous basis. This information helps us to enhance the online experience of visitors to our site. We use the statistics to understand how customers use our sites, to make it easier for you and other visitors to use, to monitor our site's performance and to improve our web site. We will also use information collected by cookies to target the delivery to you of information about our products and services that may be of interest to you. You will not be sent any promotional materials from any of our promotions that are no longer being offered in the marketplace.

To assist you, cookies help us remember who you are through your browser settings, while saving your passwords and preferences so you don't have to enter them each time; essentially, cookies save you time. We never combine information gathered by a cookie with personally identifiable information. 

The use of cookies is an industry standard and you will find that most major web sites use cookies and most major browsers are set up to accept them. If you wish, you can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent.

You do not need to accept cookies to visit our site. However, should you choose not to accept these cookies, your experience at our site (and other web sites) may be diminished and some features may not work properly.  

**How We Safeguard Your Information**

The information you provide to us on our web site is securely maintained and kept confidential. Information is retained in secure facilities, and protected from unauthorized access. We provide technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your information against loss, misuse, and unauthorized access or disclosure. 

For some services, SaskTel uses service providers located in another country to process and store information related to that service and as a result foreign governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through the laws of that country.  

**Children**

The privacy of children is important to us. We encourage parents to review our Privacy Statement and our Legal Notices and User Agreement documents. We ask that children do not submit any personal information to us. Our services are intended for individuals who can form legally binding contracts. SaskTel does not use our web site to intentionally collect or use a child's personal data.

As an added protection for children, on any of our commercial web sites or online services directed to children under 13 years of age, we will obtain the permission of a parent or legal guardian before collecting, using or disclosing any personally-identifiable information about a child, e.g., for participation in contests or promotions.

SaskTel is also a sponsor of Project Cleanfeed Canada, an initiative involving Canada's largest Internet Service Providers who have teamed up with Cybertip.ca to protect their customers from inadvertently visiting foreign web-sites that contain images of children being sexually abused and that are beyond the jurisdiction of Canadian legal authorities. For more information on Project Cleanfeed Canada, please see Cybertip’s Web site: <http://www.cybertip.ca/app/en/>  

**Links to Other Web Sites**

This web site may contain links to other sites that are not governed by this Privacy Statement. Please be aware that SaskTel is not responsible for the privacy practices of other such sites. This policy applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are moving to another web site. It is important for you to read the Privacy Statement and terms of use for each site you visit to ensure you are comfortable with how they might use your personal information. SaskTel provides links to you only as a convenience, and the inclusion of any link does not imply endorsement, investigation, verification or approval of such web sites, products, services, or publications by SaskTel.   

Questions or Concerns 

SaskTel welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. Please contact us if you have questions about privacy and usage that were not answered here. You may address these concerns, in writing to us: 

Chief Privacy Officer   
SaskTel   
13th Floor, 2121 Saskatchewan Drive   
Regina , SK. S4P 3Y2   
e-mail: [privacy.matters@sasktel.sk.ca ](mailto:privacy.matters@sasktel.sk.ca)

If this does not resolve your concern to your satisfaction, you may contact the Saskatchewan Information and Privacy by writing to: 

Saskatchewan Information and Privacy Commissioner   
#503 - 1801 Hamilton St.   
Regina , Saskatchewan   
S4P 4B4 

Last Modified: March 16, 2012
